{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "My parents always let me ________ what I think I should.",
      "a": "Doing",
      "b": "Do",
      "c": "To Do",
      "d": "For doing",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "Following pattern: Let somebody do something.",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Going on this diet has really __________ me good. I've lost weight and I feel fantanstic!",
      "a": "made",
      "b": "taken",
      "c": "\bdone",
      "d": "had",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "Do sb good (idiom): to benefit someone.",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "She ________ aerobics every day.",
      "a": "does",
      "b": "is doing",
      "c": "is going to do",
      "d": "do",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "- Use the Simple Present to express the idea that an action is repeated or usual. The action can be a habit, a hobby, a daily event, a scheduled event or something that often happens\n+ Sign word: everyday, usually, always, often, sometimes, seldom, rarely, never, once a week, twice a week.",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Every morning he ________ morning exercises.",
      "a": "do",
      "b": "does",
      "c": "did",
      "d": "is doing",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "- Use the Simple Present to express the idea that an action is repeated or usual. The action can be a habit, a hobby, a daily event, a scheduled event or something that often happens\n+ Signal word: everyday, usually, always, often, sometimes, seldom, rarely, never, once a week, twice a week",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What time_________ your sister get up?",
      "a": "does",
      "b": "do",
      "c": "what",
      "d": "is",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "-Auxiliary \"do\" helps form tense of action verb (get) in question and negative sentence:\n+ Do/don't (Simple Present) (you, they, we, two people or more, plural noun)\n+ Does/doesn't (Simple Present) (he, she, it, one person, singular noun\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "She likes sports. She always ______ aerobics every day.",
      "a": "have",
      "b": "has",
      "c": "do",
      "d": "does",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "-Aerobics: (noun) a very active type of physical exercise done to music, usually in a class\n\nDo aerobics\n\n- Use the Simple Present to express the idea that an action is repeated or usual. The action can be a habit, a hobby, a daily event, a scheduled event or something that often happens\n\n+ Signal word: today, everyday, usually, always, often, sometimes, seldom, rarely, never, once a week, twice a week…\n\n-Subject-Verb Agreement: A singular subject (she) takes a singular verb (does) whereas a plural subject takes a plural verb.\n\n-There are three ways to make the “S form”: \n\n+By adding “s” to the end of a verb (run >runs, sit >sits,see >sees, play > plays)\n\n+By adding “es” to the end of the verb that has a sibilant sound – ss, ch, x, tch, sh, zz, o (watch > watches, guess > guesses, mix > mixes; go-> goes)\n\n+By changing final “y” to “ies” after a consonant +y (study > studies, party > parties, fly > flies)\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "_______ you have Literature on Monday?",
      "a": "Do",
      "b": "Does",
      "c": "Doing",
      "d": "To do",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "-Auxiliary \"do\" helps form tense of action verb (watch) in question and negative sentence:\n+ Do/don't (Simple Present) (you, they, we, two people or more, plural noun)\n+ Does/doesn't (Simple Present) (he, she, it, one person, singular noun",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Your son ______ morning exercises everyday.",
      "a": "do",
      "b": "does",
      "c": "is doing",
      "d": "are doing",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "- Use the Simple Present to express the idea that an action is repeated or usual. The action can be a habit, a hobby, a daily event, a scheduled event or something that often happens\n\n+ Signal word: today, everyday, usually, always, often, sometimes, seldom, rarely, never, once a week, twice a week…\n\n-Subject-Verb Agreement: A singular subject (Your son) takes a singular verb (does) whereas a plural subject takes a plural verb.\n\n-There are three ways to make the “S form”:\n\n+By adding “s” to the end of a verb (run >runs, sit >sits,see >sees, play > plays)\n\n+By adding “es” to the end of the verb that has a sibilant sound – ss, ch, x, tch, sh, zz, o (watch > watches, guess > guesses, mix > mixes; go-> goes)\n\n+By changing final “y” to “ies” after a consonant +y (study > studies, party > parties, fly > flies)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What time__________ you finish your homework last night?",
      "a": "do",
      "b": "did",
      "c": "was",
      "d": "were",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "-Use the Simple Past:\n+To express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past.\n+Signal words: yesterday, last week, last year, ago, in (+ period of time in the past), when (when I was young, when I was small...)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "I hate school, the teachers make us _________ so much homework every day!",
      "a": "do",
      "b": "doing",
      "c": "to do",
      "d": "did",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "- Pattern: \"make somebody do something\".",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "11",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    }
  ]
}